Faculty Women's Club. Constitutions, by-laws, and amendments. 1932-2000.
UCLA Library Special Collections
Faculty Women's Club. Constitutions, by-laws, and amendments.
1932-1998
University Archives Record Series 694
UCLA Library Special Collections
0.4 linear ft. (1 box)
Record Series 694 contains the constitutions, by-laws, and amendments of UCLA's Faculty Women's Club.
University of California, Los Angeles. Faculty Women's Club.
Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Historical note
The Faculty Women's Club (FWC) originated as a political action group. In 1918 there were moves afoot to create a four-year college in Southern California. Women of the faculty of the Los Angeles Normal School came together and formed a Faculty Women's Club in order to help gather support for the proposed four year college particularly among women's groups in the State. In 1919 the Normal School became the Southern Branch of the University of California. Once the political objective was achieved the FWC met to consider the club's future. The club determined to continue and by the spring of 1920 the first constitution and purpose of the FWC of the Southern Branch of the University of California had been drafted. The first purpose did not include specific mention of scholarships and yet the treasurer's report for 1920-1921 includes the entry: $30.00 for Student Loan Fund. This fund, the first such fund at UCLA, was the modest beginning for the club's present scholarship program. The club has continued, without interruption, and tried to fulfill the founders' hope that it would "create a broader view and deeper interest in the civic, political and social life in our community."
UCLA Faculty Women's Club. 1999. Online. University of California, Los Angeles. Internet. 7 December 1999. http://www.alumni.ucla.edu/ASG/Support/fwcinfo.html.
Scope and Content
Record Series 694 contains the constitutions, by-laws, and amendments of UCLA's Faculty Women's Club.
This is an active record series; additional University records are expected to be added.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 4475134
- Elizabeth Klingberg., 1932-1933. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bertha Haines., 1934-1935. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Eleanor H. Johnson., 1938-1939. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Maude R. Murdoch., 1940-1941. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Clara Humphreys., 1941-1942. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Hazel Hoel., 1952-1953. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Evelyn Hodgson., 1955-1956. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Joyce S. Nelson., 1956-1957. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lillian Asimow., 1959-1960. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Louise York., 1964-1965. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Nancy Leondes., 1966-1967. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Mary Erickson., 1967-1968. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Penny Hutchinson., 1972-1973. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Pat Nagy., 1978-1979. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Helen Nefkens., 1984-1985. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Jane Cram., 1989-1990. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Elaine Wise., 1990-1991. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Elizabeth Cecchetti., 1991-1992. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Mildred Massey., 1992-1993. (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Marinette Kubeck., 1995-1996. (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Felicite Halma., 1997-1998. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Proposed ballot., Undated. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- University of California at Berkeley Women's Faculty., Undated. (Box 1, Folder 23)